so now that we know that cache blocks
need to be at aligned memory addresses
let's look at what the memory and cache
look like in terms of blocks our memory
can be seen as just a huge array of
memory locations let's say this is
location number 0 and let's say that
each location is 4 bytes wide so the
next location is at address 4 and then 8
and so on let's say that our block size
is 16 bytes that means that a possible
block in memory is this this would be
the first block this would be the second
block this would be the third block and
so on a cache then can be considered to
be a number of slots where a block can
fit in this case we have just a two
block cache so the cache size is just
equal to two block sizes so our memory
has blocks of data and their cache has
lines which are basically slots where a
block can fit so we can say for example
that block number zero can be fetched
into the cache and placed in line number
zero so when we want to make a precise
distinction between the space in the
cache where we can put a block and the
actual memory content we put there the
space in the cache is called a line and
the stuff we put there is called a block
the line size and the block size are the
same so a line is effectively a slot
where a block might fit